New calls for Australia to introduce a sugar-sweetened beverages tax have sparked an outcry from the food and beverage industry and provoked resistance from politicians.
要求澳大利亚开征含糖饮料税的新呼声，引发了食品饮料行业的强烈抗议，也招致了政界人士的抵制。
But why do health experts keep calling for a sugar-sweetened beverages (SSB) tax, and why are politicians and industry resisting it?
然而，卫生专家为什么一再呼吁开征含糖饮料（SSB）税，政界人士和业界又为什么抵制这项税？
Sugar taxes vary in design around the world in 26 countries.
全球26个国家的糖税在设计上各不相同。
In Mexico, a 10% tax on sugary drinks was introduced in 2014.
墨西哥于2014年开始对含糖饮料征收10%的税。
When the tax starts in the UK in April, there will be two bands—one for sugar content above 5g per 100ml and a second, higher tax on drinks containing more than 8g of sugar per 100ml.
英国的糖税将于4月开始征收，届时税率将分为两档：一档针对每100毫升含糖量超过5克的饮料，另一档税率更高，针对每100毫升含糖量超过8克的饮料。
In a 2018 statement on nutrition the Australian Medical Association (AMA) urged the government to introduce an SSB tax.
澳大利亚医学会（AMA）在2018年发布的一份营养声明中，敦促政府开征含糖饮料税。
This is significant because the AMA is generally conservative when it comes to health policy and often avoids controversial debates.
这一点意义重大，因为澳大利亚医学会在卫生政策方面通常态度保守，而且常常回避有争议的辩论。
But it now wants a sugar tax “as a matter of priority”.
但如今，它希望把开征糖税“作为优先事项”。
The health minister has made it clear the government will not support it, saying food labelling laws and voluntary codes of conduct to restrict food marketing to children are adequate.
卫生部长已明确表示，政府不会支持开征这项税，称食品标签法和限制向儿童推销食品的自愿行为准则已经足够。
A Labor MP also stopped short of supporting a tax, saying other strategies are needed to promote a healthy lifestyle.
一位工党议员也没有表态支持征税，称需要采取其他策略来推广健康的生活方式。
The Greens, led by former doctor Richard Di Natale, support the tax and have previously proposed a 20% increase to the price of sugary drinks.
由曾任医生的理查德·迪纳塔莱领导的绿党支持征收这项税，此前还曾提议将含糖饮料的价格提高20%。
According to Prof. Tim Gill, from the Boden Institute of Obesity, Nutrition, Exercise & Eating Disorders in Sydney, the strength of an SSB tax is that it targets an easily defined product.
在悉尼博登肥胖、营养、运动与饮食失调研究所的蒂姆·吉尔教授看来，含糖饮料税的优势在于它针对的是一种容易界定的产品。
“It’s easy to identify sugary drinks and their manufacturers, and you can tax them at their production,” he said.
“含糖饮料及其生产商都很容易识别，而且可以在生产环节对它们征税。”他说。
“There are a limited number of sugary drinks producers in Australia.
“澳大利亚的含糖饮料生产商数量有限。
A problem for governments collecting taxes can be how complicated it can be.
政府征税时，一个问题可能就在于征税会有多复杂。
If you were to try to tax every sugary food, for example, that would be very complicated to do.”
比如，假如试图对每一种含糖食品都征税，那做起来就会非常复杂。”
The government has previously used complexity as an argument against an SSB tax.
政府此前就曾把复杂性用作反对含糖饮料税的理由。
“But now with the UK, which has a similar consumption culture to ours but with a larger population and more producers, jumping on the bandwagon, that complexity argument doesn’t hold weight anymore,” Gill said.
“但如今英国也加入了这一行列，那里的消费文化与我们相似，只是人口更多、生产商也更多，这种以复杂性为由的论点就再也站不住脚了。”吉尔说。
Bureau of Statistics data shows Australia is one of the 10 highest soft-drink-consuming countries per capita.
统计局的数据显示，按人均计算，澳大利亚是软饮料消费量最高的10个国家之一。
The World Health Organisation recommends adults consume no more than six teaspoons of sugar per day, but the average Australian consumes more than double that.
世界卫生组织建议成年人每天摄入的糖不超过六茶匙，但澳大利亚人的平均摄入量是这一数量的两倍多。
A 330ml bottle of Coke contains nine teaspoons of sugar.
一瓶330毫升的可口可乐含有九茶匙糖。
A study published in the Journal of the Academy of Nutrition and Dietetics found sales of soft drinks in Melbourne’s Alfred hospital dropped 27.6% during a 17-week trial when the price of sugary drinks was increased by 20%.
发表在《营养与饮食学会杂志》上的一项研究发现，墨尔本阿尔弗雷德医院在一项为期17周的试验中将含糖饮料的价格提高了20%，其间院内软饮料的销量下降了27.6%。
Bottled water sales increased by almost the same amount.
瓶装水的销量则增长了几乎同样的幅度。
An analysis of sugary-drink purchases in Mexico conducted two years after the tax was introduced found a 5.5% drop in the first year, followed by a 9.7% decline in the second.
墨西哥开征该税两年后，一项针对该国含糖饮料购买量的分析发现，第一年购买量下降了5.5%，随后第二年下降了9.7%。
While two years is not enough to determine the long-term impact on health, the study found: “These reductions in consumption could have positive impacts on health outcomes and reductions in healthcare expenses.”
尽管两年时间还不足以确定其对健康的长期影响，但该研究发现：“消费量的这些下降可能会对健康结果产生积极影响，并减少医疗保健开支。”
Sugar-sweetened drinks and sugar generally have been associated with obesity, type 2 diabetes, cardiovascular disease, tooth decay and bone density problems.
含糖饮料以及一般意义上的糖，都被认为与肥胖、2型糖尿病、心血管疾病、蛀牙和骨密度问题有关。
The Australian Healthcare and Hospitals Association says obesity is the leading cause of preventable death or illness in Australia—above smoking.
澳大利亚医疗保健与医院协会表示，在澳大利亚，肥胖是导致可预防死亡或疾病的首要原因，排在吸烟之前。
But it will take longer-term analysis to see clear evidence of any impact of a tax on obesity levels.
但要看到征税对肥胖水平有所影响的明确证据，还需要更长期的分析。
Lobby groups from the food and beverage industry are powerful.
食品饮料行业的游说团体势力强大。
The Australian Beverages Council, the industry’s lobby group, has been fighting against a tax for years.
澳大利亚饮料理事会是该行业的游说团体，多年来一直在反对征税。
It says there is no evidence a tax will do anything to reduce obesity, and that it will cost jobs, which is a frightening message for politicians.
该理事会称，没有证据表明征税能对减少肥胖起任何作用，而且征税会造成就业岗位流失，这对政界人士来说是个可怕的信息。
The Australasian Association of Convenience Stores (AACS) described the introduction of an SSB tax in the UK as “lazy”, “flawed”, “discriminatory” and “irrational”.
澳大拉西亚便利店协会（AACS）把英国开征含糖饮料税形容为“懒惰”“有缺陷”“歧视性”和“不理性”之举。
It has ramped up its campaign to prevent such a tax in Australia.
该协会已加大活动力度，以阻止澳大利亚开征此类税。
Would introducing a sugar tax make Australia a nanny state?
开征糖税会让澳大利亚变成一个保姆式国家吗？
It depends on whether you believe the food and beverage industry has too much power.
这取决于你是否认为食品饮料行业势力过大。
Health experts argue that through advertising, product placement and political influence, the food and beverage industry has an unfair and non-transparent influence over consumer purchasing habits, and that children especially are sometimes powerless to recognise or resist it.
卫生专家认为，食品饮料行业借助广告、植入式广告和政治影响力，对消费者的购买习惯施加着不公平且不透明的影响；尤其是儿童，有时无力识别或抵制这种影响。
They say an SSB tax would hold the industry to account.
他们说，含糖饮料税会让该行业承担起责任。
Others argue people need to take personal responsibility.
另一些人则认为，人们需要自己承担责任。
A Deakin University study used economic modelling to show the increase in annual spending on sugar-sweetened drinks under a 20% tax would average $30 a person, but those in the lowest socioeconomic groups would pay $5 a year more than those in the wealthiest groups.
迪肯大学的一项研究利用经济建模表明，若征收20%的税，每人每年在含糖饮料上的支出平均将增加30澳元，但社会经济地位最低的群体每年要比最富裕的群体多付5澳元。
Researchers concluded this was a modest price to pay given the benefits—and that Australia’s lowest socioeconomic group would receive the greatest health benefits.
研究人员得出结论：考虑到所带来的益处，这点代价并不大，而且澳大利亚社会经济地位最低的群体将获得最大的健康益处。
Health experts and advocacy groups say governments could reduce the financial burden on disadvantaged people by using revenue from a tax to fund health initiatives.
卫生专家和倡导团体表示，政府可以利用税收收入资助卫生项目，从而减轻弱势人群的经济负担。